

Charuka Krishantha

Software Enginner

Experienced software engineer with a Bachelor's in Information Technology from SLIIT, recognized for my roles as a Software Engineer at Hayleys Advantis Limited and an Associate Software Engineer at Virtusa. I've also completed a productive internship at Enuri Information System, and I am currently working as a MERN stack Software Engineer at Nova Solution.

Email: charukatharindhu@gmail.com

Address: 248/7, Kaduwela Road, Malabe, Sri Lanka

Phone: +94783901888 Date of birth: Sep 3, 1997 Nationality: Srilankan

Links: linkedin.com/charuka-tharindhu, https://personal-portfolio-charuka.vercel.app/

Experience

June 2024 - present

Full Stack Developer - MERN NOVA Solution (Pvt) Ltd. Colombo

01. VENDERX POS SYSTEM

Created a specialized POS system for restaurants, optimizing order management, inventory tracking, table management, payments, and reporting.

Responsibilities:

- Contribute for developed and maintain an admin panel and user-facing web application optimized for tablet view.
- Contribute from Developed and maintain a unified backend server, structured using our proprietary boilerplate for both admin and web applications.

Technologies:

Tech stack includes Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Redux Toolkit, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, MongoDB, and AWS services like Elastic Beanstalk, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, CloudWatch, Route 53, S3 Bucket, Load Balancer

02. AMAZON, ALIBABA, AND EBAY WEB SCRAPERS FOR PLATFORM-PROFIT

PLATFORM-PROFTR simplifies product research for drop shippers by consolidating Alibaba, Amazon, and eBay data into one platform

Responsibilities:

- Lindependently developed and maintain all three web scrapers from inception to completion.
- Scrapped all product details based on specific categories, navigating page by page with pagination.
- Improved scraper performance by using Multithreading and preventing bot detection through rotating user-agents and setup sleep-time for each request. Saved all scraped product details in MongoDB after each category was successfully scraped.
- Run all three scrappers automatically at midnight by using apscheduler

Technologies:

Python 3.12, BeautifulSoup4, Requests 2.3, Selenium, Flask and Packages (Pymongo, random, apscheduler, threading, ThreadPoolExecutor) and AWS services like Elastic Beanstalk, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, CloudWatch, Route 53, Reverse Proxy(Nginx) S3 Bucket, Load Balancer

Dec 2023 - June 2024

Full Stack Developer - MERN **Freelance Projects**

01. SUPERSCONTO

Supersconto web application designed to offer detailed information on discounted products within the city of Milan in Italy.

Responsibilities:

Developed and maintain both an admin panel and a user-facing web application, both admin and web app powered by a single backend server.

Technologies:

Tech stack includes Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Next.js, Redux Toolkit, Material UI, MongoDB, and AWS S3 for storage, and AWS EC2 for hosting with PM2 server and SSL certification.

Live URL

Web-app: www.supersconto24.com

Admin-panel: www.dashboard.supersconto24.com

02. BLOONSOO

operations at Welisara and Sedawatta.

Bloonsoo expanded into flights, villas, and day outings, with an admin panel for super and hotel admins, integrating

user authentication, Google Maps, and payments. Responsibilities:

S3 for storage, and AWS EC2 for hosting with PM2 server and SSL certification.

Developed and maintain both an admin panel and a user-facing web application, both admin and web app powered by a single backend server.

Technologies: Tech stack includes Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Next.js, Redux Toolkit, Material UI, MongoDB, and AWS

April 2023 - June 2024

Software Engineer Hayleys Advanties Limited, Colombo

01. INLAND CONTAINER DEPO

Developed and maintained an application for Logistic International Limited, supporting container depot

- Conducted production releases, debugged issues, providing 24/7 support for both live systems.
- Technologies: Used Angular.js, ASP.NET 4.2, NativeScript, WCF services, SQL, and development tools such as Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, MySQL Server Management Studio, and GitHub.

March 2022 - April 2023 **Associate Software Engineer**

Virtusa (Pvt) Ltd Colombo

Full Stack Developer Intern

01. ENTERPRISE DIGITAL BOT Responsibilities:

Developed and maintained Lisa, Virtusa's internal support bot, streamlining issue resolution across HR,

- IT, Finance, and technical domains, Contributing as a ServiceNow and backend developer.
- Technologies ASP.NET core, Azure function, Azure DevOps, ServiceNow platform

July 2021 - March 2022

01. TECHIOBZ.CO

Enuri Information System (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo

TechJobz.co is an innovative research project designed for IT job seekers. Responsibilities:

As a full-stack developer, I contributed to creating a feature-rich platform similar to LinkedIn, Top Jobs, and Stack Overflow, focusing on user-friendly job search capabilities.

Technologies:

React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Next.js, MongoDB, SendGrid API, Meterial UI,JWT, PayHere payment gateway, SendGrid API, Github.

BSc (Hons) Degree in Information Technology

Education

Live URL: web-app: www.pathintech.com

Jun 2018 - Dec 2022

Sri Lanka Institute Of Information Technology, Kandy Road, Malabe Jan 2014 - Aug 2016 Advance Level Examination

> T/Abayapura Maha Vidyalaya, Trincomalee Engineering Technology Stream

Typescript (TS), JavaScript (JS), React.js, Node.js, Python, Next.js, Express.js, C#, ASP.Net

Core < Anguler.js

Skills

Unit Test, Jest, ES10 MongoDB, MySQL Cloud Services: AWS, Azure, Render, Vercel,

Git, Agile, Jira, Swagger, Postman, JWT, REST, JSON

References

- I. Lalindu Peris: Lead Consultant Technology at Virtusa, Phone:+94775417372, Email: Lpeirisvirtusa.com
- 2. Roshan Panditha: Associate Tech Lead at 99x. Phone: +94 715152202
- 3. Pathum Kalham: Associate Technical Lead EFutures Private Limited, Phone: +94 71 756 5094, Email: pathumsimpsongmail.com